(
"ai_sub_version": "2.9.1",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 7,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 15,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch"
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 5,
"max": 5,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
Mori Calliope Birthday Live
01 AZKi
02 Nerissa Ravencroft
03 Tokino Sora
04 Hoshimachi Suisei
05 Mori Calliope
Uncut Rock!!
[Song: Rivals and Equals]
Base instincts take control
Like primal ways of a warrior
Is it glory you're after, like me?
Underestimated everywhere I turn
Taking aim but it doesn't make a difference at all
I got a million different enemies I cannot recall
You're rocking up to a battle when you know that you'll fall
Hidden motivation, watch it all burn
I gotta tell you
I never liked you
Now would I lie to you?
Let me ignite you
When thunder crashes down
When the world caves under my pressure
There'll be no one to save
Where is your pride, your human will to survive?
Was it just empty words...
...for your grave?
I reach inside this soul
Now all that remains
Is delusion and decay
Cuz of you, I live...
...this way!
We're not rivals
We're not equals
We're not equals!
Lightning never strikes twice in the same spot
So go ahead and run up on me till you get your shot
I see the weapon that you're hiding, come on ready or not
Another life and you would never give a second thought
Thinkin' your pride's different than mine
Ticking all your vital signs off
But we still gotta protect all our friends from our enemies
Wouldn't you agree?
Forged in fires of hell, god can't betray you
If I'm a fallen angel, what does that make you?
I'm not debasing myself to see the same view
When it's your pride on the line, no one can save you from mine
We're not rivals!
We're not equals!
ハロー、みなさん！
Hello, everyone!
Yeah yeah!
Woo! This is... well thank... thank you!
森カリオペです！Thank you so much everybody for coming to my birthday live!
This is Mori Calliope! Thank you so much everyone for coming to my birthday live!
Here's the hashtag!
UncutRock, right here, right here, right here!
Check it out, everybody!
Today's theme is obviously birthday, right?
It's my birthday, and so...
If you look behind us, we've got stones!
Oh my gosh!
What kind of stones, I wonder? Maybe birthday stones?
Depending on the guest, I suppose. Mori Calliope's is diamond.
So...
Of course, you will see white behind me.
Yes, and the idea is to sing original songs with guests,
and also my own songs. And...
I'm looking at the comments right now. Now, the show is in very high quality, so
there's like a pretty big lag, but I'm looking. Woo, woo!
There's a lot of clapping.
Holy cannoli!
Holy cannoli is right! こんばんは、こんばんは！
Holy cannoli is right! Good evening, good evening!
コメント見てます！
I'm reading the comments!
わあ、すごい！Happy birthday, happy birthday! Happy birthday wish, ありがとうございます！
Wow, amazing! Happy birthday, happy birthday! Thank you so much for the birthday wishes!
And you know what, behind me is not only stones,
but I also have a fabulous band joining me!
Yes, that's right! Live band.
Thank you so much to the band for coming.
Now, in particular,
we have somebody Mori Calliope really respects.
Today, Park-san is here with us!
カリちゃん、ハッピーバースデー。
Calli-chan, happy birthday.
Thank you!
今日はよろしくお願いします。
I look forward to working with you today.
よろしくお願いします！
I look forward to working with you, too!
Park-san is one of my favorite bass players ever.
He's done two songs for me.
In particular, Orpheus and Sepia.
オルフェウスとセピアのベースやってくれました。
He played the bass for 'Orpheus' and 'Sepia'.
Park-sanはすごいリスペクトしてます。はい。
I really respect Park-san. Yes.
But I have so many wonderful members in the band today,
and also guests as well,
and I don't want to take up too much more time, but...
Anyway, we should probably sing with guests
because I want to showcase all that we've been practicing together.
So...
let's go ahead and begin!
The first guest, come on!
閉ざした世界
A closed world,
かすかに聞こえる音
a sound heard faintly.
世界で二人きりみたいだ
It's like we're the only two in the world.
届きそうな手
A hand that seems to reach...
すれ違った心が
...hearts that passed each other...
ちょっと痛むんだ
...hurt a little.
ここで待って
Wait here.
決められないままで
Without being able to decide,
戸惑い溢れてしまうよ
bewilderment overflows.
もう何度も繰り返した
I've repeated this so many times,
零れた想いを数えて
counting the spilled thoughts.
何度も繰り返した
I've repeated this so many times,
世界
The world,
the world,
開くのを待っている
waiting for it to open.
壊れた世界
A broken world,
回り続ける針は
the needle keeps spinning,
ちぎれた意識
connecting my torn...
繋いでいく
...consciousness.
歪んだ金属音
A distorted metal sound...
鳴り響く心に
...ringing in my heart...
ちょっと響くんだ
...echoes a little.
ここで待って
Wait here.
記憶繋げないまま
Without being able to connect the memories...
狂って 壊れてしまうよ
...I'll go mad and be destroyed.
もう何度も繰り返した
I've already repeated it so many times...
神様に願いをかけて
...making a wish to God...
何度も繰り返した
...repeating it over and over again.
世界 世界
Waiting for...
開くのを待っている
...the world, the world to open.
もうなんにもいらないから
Because I don't need anything anymore...
零れた想いは愛おしい
...the spilled feelings are precious.
何度も繰り返した
I've already repeated it so many times...
世界 世界
Waiting for...
開くのを...
...the world, the world to open...
もう何度も繰り返した
I've already repeated it so many times...
神様に願いをかけて
...making a wish to God...
何度も繰り返して
...repeating it over and over again.
世界 世界
Waiting for...
開くのを待っている
...the world, the world to open.
Yeah yeah yeah! Yay!
Our first guest is AZKi-senpai!
AZKi!
右手にマイク、左手に地図、あなたのハートをゼロゲッサー！
With a mic in my right hand, a map in my left,
Zeroguessar of your heart!
カリオペちゃん、ハッピーバースデー！
Calliope-chan, Happy Birthday!
ありがとうございます！バースデーです！誕生日です！
Thank you so much!
It's my birthday! Yes, my birthday!
誕生日ガール！
ありがとうございます。
Birthday girl!
Thank you very much.
さっき一緒に歌った曲、大好きです。
I absolutely love the song we just sang together.
ありがとうございます！なんと、AZKiのオリジナル曲を一緒に歌わせていただきました！
Thank you so much! Amazingly, I got to sing
AZKi's original song together with you!
そうですね。ずっとバンドアレンジで歌いたかったから、選びました。
That's right. I've always wanted to sing it
with a band arrangement, so I chose it.
めっちゃ熱かったです！
やったー！
It was super hot!
Yay!
楽しかったよね。バンドの演奏も凄かったです。
It was so fun, wasn't it?
The band's performance was amazing too!
ありがとうございます。イェーイ！
Thank you so much. Yay!
あ、ちなみに、ステージと見てほしい。
Ah, by the way, I want you to look at the stage.
いや、凄い！めちゃくちゃピカピカ光ってる！
Wow, amazing!
It's shining so brightly!
ピカピカストーン！ピカピカストーン！
Sparkling stone! Sparkling stone!
そうですよね。素敵なステージですよね。
素敵なステージです。
That's right. It's a wonderful stage, isn't it?
It's a wonderful stage.
ちなみに...
ちなみに？
By the way...
By the way?
AZKi先輩の誕生石は知ってる？
AZKiの誕生石は...
Do you know AZKi-senpai's birthstone?
AZKi's birthstone is...
7月なんですけど、ルビー！ルビー、この色！
I'm born in July, so it's Ruby!
Ruby, this color!
そう、なりました！すごい！この色が変わるんです、今日は。
Yes, it changed! Amazing!
The color changes today.
すごい！めっちゃ赤です。
そうですね。めっちゃ綺麗だから、一緒に写真撮りたい。
Amazing! It's super red.
Yes, since it's so beautiful, let's take a photo.
あ、撮りたい！撮りたい、せっかく！
Take screenshots! Screenshots!
Ah, I want to! Let's do it!
いい感じです。
イェーイ！イェーイ、イェーイ、イェーイ！
Looking good!
Yay! Yay, yay, yay!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
じゃあ、まあ、生ライブだから、やっぱ、水飲みたいと思う。
Well, since it's a live concert,
I really want to drink some water.
水飲もう！
乾杯！水乾杯です。
Let's drink some water!
Cheers! A toast with water.
はい、乾杯！
Cheers!
Yes, cheers!
Mmm!
じゃあ次、次の曲。
Now, the next song.
お、次の曲は何だろうな？
Oh, I wonder what the next song is?
もう一曲ありますよね、一緒に。
あります！
We have one more song together, don't we?
We do!
そう、さっきAZKi先輩のオリ曲歌いましたね。
はい、そうです。
Yes, we just sang AZKi-senpai's original song, right?
Yes, that's right.
今回は、カリオペのオリ曲です。
歌わせていただきます！
This time, it's Calliope's original song.
I will be singing it with you!
The next song is Calliope's original, 'Miraijima'!
「未来島」！
'Miraijima'!
危険な海に浮かぶ島　エッグヘッドへ
To Egghead, an island floating in a dangerous sea
世界変える未来島のLabo
The Lab of the future island that will change the world
最高の発明 叶えるよ願望
The greatest inventions will grant your desires
未来のお宝 探しちゃおう
Let's look for the treasures of the future
天才が引き起こす発想の奇跡
A miracle of ideas brought about by a genius
脳内終わらせない夢 of Fantasy
An endless fantasy of dreams inside the brain
世界ひっくり返るテクノロジー
Technology that turns the world upside down
大体叶えちゃうラボラトリー
A laboratory that makes almost anything come true
シャッカ リリス エジソン
Shaka, Lilith, Edison...
ピタゴラス アトラス ヨーク 6人のサテライト
...Pythagoras, Atlas, York—the six satellites!
湧き出すアイデア 止まらない
The gushing ideas won't stop
忙しすぎてネコの手も借りたい
We're so busy we'd even take a cat's help
海も何も超えていく海賊を
The pirates who transcend the seas and everything else
常識変えていく発明を
The inventions that change common sense
そんな奴らに憧れてきた
I've always admired those kinds of people
次は誰が王になる
Who will become the King next?
無限の夢 未来の知恵
Infinite dreams, future wisdom
煌めきを巻き起こせ エッグヘッド
Stir up the sparkle on Egghead!
無限の夢 未来の知恵
Infinite dreams, future wisdom
過去の世界も飛び越して
Leaping even past the worlds of the past!
ベガパンク 生み出すよアイデア ベガパンク
Vegapunk! Generating ideas, Vegapunk!
ベガパンク！ 革命をここから ベガパンク！ Go!
Vegapunk! Revolution starts here, Vegapunk! Go!
危険な海に浮かぶ島へ Head!
Head to the island floating in a dangerous sea!
世界を変える未来島のラボへ
To the lab on Future Island that will change the world!
This mind is undefeated,
until my goal's completed. Let's keep on searching for the treasure of to come!
Genius! A miracle idea, gotta set it free!
Sensuous! Fantastic dreams are burning up inside of me!
Rebellious! We'll turn the world around with new technology!
Fabulous! Laboratory cast upon the sea!
Representing evil and the contents of mind, writing the knowledge, greed and violent satellites.
Ideas can't stop flushing out, still thinking they might could use a hand or two, I'm busy working into the night!
The pirate king who braves the ocean while in search of elation
A ruler of invention that can modify your reason
Once washed in jealousy, but someday I've got to be
Next on the throne, I know what I've got to do!
無限の夢 未来の知恵
Infinite dreams, wisdom of the future
ひらめきを巻き起こせ Ahead!
Create a spark of inspiration, ahead!
無限の夢 未来の知恵
Infinite dreams, wisdom of the future
過去も世界も飛び越して
Leaping over the past and the world!
ベガパンク！ 生み出すよアイデア
Vegapunk! I'll create ideas!
ベガパンク！
Vegapunk!
ベガパンク！ 革命をここから ベガパンク！
Vegapunk! Revolution starts here, Vegapunk!
言うこと聞かなきゃ 振りかざす正義
If you don't listen, I'll brandish my justice
世界を守る軍団の正義
The justice of the army protecting the world
秘密巡る怪しい企み
A suspicious conspiracy surrounding secrets
過去の記憶に隠された狂気
Madness hidden within past memories
真実を暴く 危険な遊戯
A dangerous game to uncover the truth
謎に満ちた いつかの夢のエネルギー
Filled with mystery, the dream energy of someday
天才が見せる世界の形
The shape of the world shown by a genius
どこへ向かう未来の島へ
To the Future Island, where are we heading?
Thank you, AZKi-senpai! Bye bye! See you later!
Everybody welcome to the stage, Sora-senpai!
okey dokey 返事はいいけど
Okey dokey, your reply is fine, but
冗談なら笑えないよ
I can't laugh if it's a joke.
渋滞 曖昧 どっちを向いちゃうの
Ambiguous traffic jam, which way are we facing?
蜃気楼に手を伸ばした
Reaching out to a mirage.
微熱のような夢物語
A dream story like a slight fever,
私に構って
Care for me,
教えてよ恋の先を！
tell me what's beyond love!
拡がって収まんない universe
Spreading out, an unstoppable universe...
君の存在は
Your existence
私の将来までも
has stepped into even my future,
踏み込んだのよ付き合ってよね
go out with me, okay?
一切合切 dance dance dance
Everything and anything, dance, dance, dance!
we are dancing reed
夢中になって絡み合ったゼログラビティ
Becoming obsessed and intertwined, zero gravity.
構わず dance dance dance
Without caring, dance, dance, dance!
just a dance just a dance
声は闇に預けたままで
My voice is left in the darkness.
目を覚ましても離れないで
Even when I wake up, don't leave me.
Yes! Our second guest is そら先輩！
Yes! Our second guest is Sora-senpai!
はい！みんな、こんそめー！ときのそらです！
Hi! Hello everyone, I'm Tokino Sora!
カリちゃん、ハッピーバースデー！
Calli-chan, happy birthday!
Thank you!
そら大先輩、本当にありがとうございます。ずっと一緒に歌いたかったから...
Sora-senpai, thank you so much! I've always wanted to sing with you...
あ、本当ですか？ありがとう！
Oh, really? Thank you!
嬉しい。まじで。やった。ヘイ、ヘイ、ヘイ！
I'm so happy, seriously! Yes! Hey, hey, hey!
ヘイ、ヘイ、ヘイ！
Hey, hey, hey!
可愛いよね。すごいたくさん踊りました。
So cute! We danced a lot!
あ、踊ったね！
Yeah, we did!
アイドル、わあ。ドキドキ。
An idol, wow. My heart is pounding.
ドキドキ？
Pounding?
Yes. お、お、やっぱりXトレンド...
Yes. Oh, of course, X trends...
...X trending number three in Japan!
お、コングラチュレーション！
Oh, congratulations!
日本のトレンド。やったー！
Trending in Japan! Yay!
やったー！
Yay!
ありがとう！たくさん使ってね、please ハッシュタグ。
Thank you! Please use the hashtag a lot!
Thank you so much! I'm so happy. ありがとう。
Thank you so much! I'm so happy. Thank you.
今回は大好きな曲、一緒に歌いました。「Dancing Reed」！
This time we sang my favorite song together, "Dancing Reed"!
Dancing Reed! すごいパーティーハッピーな曲ですよね。大好きです！
Dancing Reed! It's such a happy party song. I love it!
ダンスアブル！
Danceable!
ダンスアブル！めっちゃ良かった。
Danceable! It was so good.
そして、ほら。エメラルド来た！
And look, the emeralds are here!
ねー！綺麗！緑！エメラルド！
Yeah! So pretty! Green emeralds!
誕生石ですよね。そう、5月の誕生石、エメラルドです。
It's the birthstone, right? Yes, May's birthstone is emerald.
エメラルド。おお、すごい良い発音。ナイスイングリッシュ！
Emerald. Wow, what great pronunciation. Nice English!
本当？ありがとう！
Really? Thank you!
Nice English. Very good. そうですよね。
Nice English. Very good. Exactly.
ちなみに、写真撮ろうか？
By the way, shall we take a picture?
あ、撮る！
Oh, let's!
Let's do it!
いいね。
Nice.
イェーイ！
Yay!
写真もアップしてね、X。
Please post the photos on X too.
よろしくね！
We're counting on you!
よろしくね。わあ、楽しい！じゃあ、水飲みましょう。
We're counting on you. Wow, this is fun! Let's drink some water.
お、水！乾杯！
Oh, water! Cheers!
乾杯！
Cheers!
飲んだ方がいいっすよね。
It's best to stay hydrated.
そうね。水は大事。
Indeed. Water is important.
そうだよ。あー、楽しいな。生ライブ。
Exactly. Ah, this is so fun, a live concert!
楽しいね！
It is fun!
もう一曲一緒に歌いたいんですけど、大丈夫ですか？
I'd love to sing one more song with you, is that okay?
もちろん！
Of course!
Let's do it, okay?
Now, everyone, please listen to this next song.
You'll understand why I chose it because Sora-senpai is in the PV for this song.
Please enjoy my original song, "Dawn Blue".
つかまえて、ほら
Catch it, look!
この shooting star
At this shooting star...
A world of our fiction awaits...
ずっと同じ毎日に迷いがあっても
Even if there's hesitation in the same daily routine,
気づかないふりをしてたんだ
I always pretended not to notice.
ほんのちょっとの勇気がまだ出せなくて
I couldn't put forth even an ounce of courage,
まどろむ宇宙で彷徨っていた
so I dreamily drifted through space.
夜空に浮かぶ
Floating in the night sky,
星に願いをかけるんだ
I wish upon that star.
I hope...
抱いている夢を絶対諦めたくない
I never want to give up on the dream I hold dear,
走り出すから
so I'll begin this journey.
追いかけて 今 あの shooting star
Chase after that shooting star right now!
見たことのない ストーリー
As we move forward to a brand new story,
進んでいくんだ
hoping that someday,
いつの 日にか きっと
it will definitely
描いた セカイ へ
bring us to the world that we dreamed of,
辿り着けるように
so that we can reach it.
Let go of the days you thought mattered so
Life goes on, tomorrow's rolling in
Is it the world we know, or...
...sought so long
...we sought so long.
もっと誰でもない自分になりたいんだ
I want to become a self that is more than anyone else,
新しい風が心を揺らした
A new breeze shook my heart.
It takes something to believe
the wish we were promised could really come to life
And so, if this is how the story goes
To find that strength inside, I'll remember who I was back then
you took my hand, and you said
つかまえて、ほら このshooting star
Catch it, look, this shooting star.
さあ、まずは一歩踏み出して恐れずにゆこう
Come on, first take one step forward and go without fear.
いつの日にかきっと
Someday, for sure...
まだ見ぬ世界へ辿り着けるように
so that I can reach the world I haven't seen yet.
夜明けに咲いた月が
The moon that bloomed at dawn
眩いブルーの空に溶けてく
is melting into the dazzling blue sky.
You and I, an undecided future
doesn't matter if the final truth hurts
もうすぐ朝が動き出すから
Because the morning will move soon.
抱きしめて 今 このshooting star
Hold it now, this shooting star.
3, 2, 1...
ダウトとアンチに浴びせかける My honey
Showering doubt and antis with my honey
愛想を尽かす バラのタトゥー
Losing interest, a rose tattoo
口移し流し込む 罪の味
Pouring directly mouth-to-mouth, the taste of sin
共犯ね これであなたは
We're accomplices, so with this, you...
私に
...for me,
私にふさわしい人になりました
...have become the perfect person for me.
Right, you, left, me, eyes, you
So we did it, did it, did it, did it, stop.
I love you, You're my god
I love you, You're my boy
裏の顔をもって あなたを僕に染め抜く
Showing your hidden face, I'll dye you in my colors
I love you, You're my god
I love you, You're my boy
その味 知る前にはもう戻れない
Before knowing that taste, I can no longer return
そう 愛してみて どうかこんな僕を
Yes, try to love me, please, someone like me
愛してみて どうかこんな私を
Try to love me, please, someone like me
君、君、君、君、君ら
You, you, you, you, all of you
Hey! Hey! Come on, everybody! Woo! Alright! Yeah, yeah! 皆さん、welcome シドさんとカリオペの3D Birthday Live!
Hey! Hey! Come on, everybody! Woo! Alright! Yeah, yeah! Everyone, welcome to Shudo and Calliope's 3D Birthday Live!
Thank you!
狂わし合う様 癒やし合うように
As if driving each other mad, as if healing each other
求め合ってしまうのよ しょうがないじゃない
We end up seeking each other, it can't be helped, right?
与えられた天国より 選んだ地獄を
Rather than a given heaven, the hell we chose
あなたと二人ならどこまでも
If it's with you, we'll go anywhere
I love you, You're my god
I love you, You're my boy
堕ちていく
Falling down
I love you, You're my god
I love you, You're my boy
あなたを知って全ては過去になる
Knowing you, everything becomes the past
I love you, You're my god
真実に満ちた未来を創ろうね
Let's create a future filled with truth
そう、愛しきって どうかこんな僕を
Yes, love me completely, please, someone like me
愛しきって どうかこんな私を
Love me completely, please, someone like me
君、君、君、君、君ら
You, you, you, you, all of you
そう、愛し合ってしまったこんな僕ら
Yes, we who ended up loving each other
愛の果てに別れを告げ
At the end of love, bid farewell
君、君、君、君、君ら
You, you, you, you, all of you
皆さん、どう思いましたか？
Everyone, what did you think?
ありがとうございます！楽しかった！
Thank you very much! That was fun!
Super special guest, シドさんが来ました！
Our super special guest, Shudo-san is here!
こんにちはー！デッドビーツの皆さんこんにちは、シドです！
Hello! Hello, Deadbeats, I'm Shudo!
Yes! 自己紹介お願いします！
Yes! Please introduce yourself!
はい、え、僕はですね、音楽をやってますシドでございます！
Yes, well, I am Shudo, and I make music!
そして、ハッピーバースデー、カリオペさん！おめでとう！ / Thank you! ありがとうございます！
And, Happy Birthday, Calliope-san! Congratulations! / Thank you! Thank you so much!
ライブも最高です！あ、ちなみにハイタッチしたいんですけど、いいんですか？
The live show is awesome too! Ah, by the way, I want to do a high-touch, is it okay?
あ、いきますか？いきますか？やった、はい、せーの！
Oh, shall we? Shall we? Yay, okay, on three!
よいしょ！えい！えーい！いい感じ！
Here we go! Ey! Ey! Nice!
ありがとうございます。ありがとうございます、イェーイ。
Thank you very much. Thank you very much, yay.
ちなみにシドさんは音楽活動いろいろやってます。ね、どんな活動やってますか？
By the way, Shudo-san, you do various music activities. What kind of activities do you do?
そうですね、僕はボカロPですね、ボーカロイドで楽曲を作ったり、シンガーソングライターとして歌を歌わせていただいたり、そして色んな方に楽曲を提供したり、そんな活動をさせていただいております。
Right, well, I'm a Vocalo-P, making songs with Vocaloid, singing as a singer-songwriter, and also providing songs for various people. That's the kind of work I do.
イェーイ。もちろん私は知ってるけど、大ファンだからね。
Yay. Of course, I know that, since I'm a big fan.
嬉しい！ライブも以前来ていただきまして。
I'm so happy! You also came to my live show before.
そうですね、武道館ライブめっちゃ楽しかった！
Yes, the Budokan live was so much fun!
いや、ありがとうございました！本当に僕も楽しくて、めちゃくちゃ盛り上がったんで、いや嬉しいです、今日出られて。
No, thank you so much! I also had a lot of fun, and it was so hyped, so I'm really happy to be here today.
こちらこそ！私もすごい嬉しいですね。あの、
Same here! I'm really happy too. Um...
このステージ、どう思いますか？
...what do you think of this stage?
ねえ、これすごいですよね。後ろからこの高さも含めて。僕ちょっと高いところ苦手なんで、落ちないように気をつけながらやらないと、と思うんですけど、最高ですこれ。
Yeah, this is amazing, isn't it? Including the height from the back. I'm a bit bad with high places, so I have to be careful not to fall, but this is the best.
かなり高いけど気をつけてね。 / 気をつけます。下見えないから。 / やべえ。
It's pretty high, so be careful. / I'll be careful. I can't see the bottom. / Crazy.
え、でも、あ、そういえば、テーマが誕生日だから、ちょっと知りたい。シドさんの誕生日はいつですか？
Oh, but, ah, by the way, since the theme is birthdays, I'd like to know. When is your birthday, Shudo-san?
僕の誕生日、9月ですね、September。September! September。
My birthday is in September. September! September.
Septemberですね。 / はい。
September, right? / Yes.
Septemberの誕生石はサファイアです。もうほら、ステージはサファイア！ / あ！そういうことだったんだ、これ。
The birthstone of September is sapphire. See, the stage is sapphire! / Ah! So that's what this was.
僕に合わせて？ありがとうございます。たまたまですけど、服もこの青で、帽子も青であったんで。
To match me? Thank you very much. It's a coincidence, but my clothes are blue, and my hat is blue too.
相性がいい！嬉しい。そうですね、ありがとうございます。すごい、めっちゃいい感じですね。
Great compatibility! I'm glad. Indeed, thank you very much. Awesome, it feels really good.
次の曲は、シドさんが書き下ろしてくれたやつですね。
The next song is the one that Shudo-san wrote for me, right?
そうですね。僕がすごくカリオペさんの楽曲、大好きなレベルなんですけど、カリオペさんのカッコよくて強くて美しい、そんなところを引き出せるような楽曲で作らせていただいた曲でございます。
That's right. I love your music so much, but I made this song to bring out your cool, strong, and beautiful sides.
めっちゃいい曲本当に！大好きな曲だから、本当に感謝してます。 / 嬉しい、ありがとうございます。
It's a really great song, seriously! It's one of my favorites, so I'm truly grateful. / I'm glad, thank you.
今回、一緒に歌いたいと思います！ / 初めてですね、一緒に歌うのは、これはね。
This time, I'd like us to sing it together! / It's our first time singing together, isn't it?
初めてで、なかなかレアなのではないでしょうか。大丈夫ですか？ / はい、ありがとうございます。
First time, so it's quite rare, isn't it? Are you ready? / Yes, thank you.
オッケー、じゃ次の曲に行く前に、みんなに伝えたいことありますか？
Okay, before we go to the next song, is there anything you'd like to say to everyone?
はい、そうですね。僕こう、カリオペさんと何度かコラボさせていただいているんですけど、デッドビーツの皆さん含め、本当に温かく迎え入れていただいて、すごく嬉しいです。今回ライブもこうやってやらせていただいて、皆さん一緒に盛り上がってくれたら嬉しいです。そして改めて...
Yes, indeed. I've collaborated with Calliope-san a few times now, but everyone, including the Deadbeats, has welcomed me so warmly, and I'm really happy. I'm glad to perform live like this today, and I hope everyone gets hyped up with us. And once again...
カリさん呼んでくれてありがとうございます！
Calli-san, thank you for inviting me!
いえいえ、こちらこそ！
No, thank you!
じゃあ、それで聞いてくださいね。でも、しゅどうさん？
Now, please listen to this. But, Syudou-san?
紹介してください！
Please introduce it!
それではお聴きください。
Then please listen.
LET'S JUST CRASH!
Hey hey, everyone!
Yeah! Let's go!
Let's go! Hey!
You got eyes and ears but you don't look or listen!
In other words, you're useless, every last one of you!
And that is why I'm gonna send you all to hell!
All of humanity!
最悪を装って登場 そういうんじゃねえ
Appearing dressed as the worst, it's not like that
How unjust! Disgusted! You'll forget, so don't waste your sound!
Get get get get get it, it's my turn, go and share, somebody's gotta pay while I live in the pain, like me now, I'm the one you can't tame, ah?
天才で最低の天災 そういうんでいい
A genius and the worst disaster, that's fine to call me
想いが募る場所に花咲く
Flowers bloom where feelings grow stronger
カラー
Color
Let's try, get back! Get trapped! 新しい敵を投げつけていくんだ
Let's try, get back! Get trapped! I'll throw new enemies at them
Let's just crash! 退屈な殻から殻に
Let's just crash! From a boring shell to another shell
All right! Lose control! 美しく散りそう
All right! Lose control! About to scatter beautifully
Heads will roll! 逃げ出してやるよ
Heads will roll! I'm going to run away
誰だいったい？ 誰だってどうしたって この理想は無理だろって
Who on earth is it? No matter who, no matter what, they say this ideal is impossible
叶えてこうぜ
Let's make it come true
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
One, five, yeah, get, plus two, let's play!
正解不正解の回答 どうだっていい
Correct and incorrect answers, I don't care either way
そんなんとっくに超えた場所に俺は立っている
I'm standing in a place far beyond that
Millions of problems, everybody's got 'em, and they can't be satisfied until somebody's at the bottom, so what, you think you're special 'cause you got some greedy hunger, we ain't getting any younger, thinking 'Let's just crash!'
心が通う時に魂が先へ
Sometimes our souls go forward when our hearts connect
Let's try, get back! Get trapped! 新しい敵を投げつけていくんだ
Let's try, get back! Get trapped! I'll throw new enemies at them
俺が通る今すぐにどけ！
I'm passing through right now, get out of the way!
Let's try, get back! Get trapped! 新しい敵を投げつけていくんだ
Let's try, get back! Get trapped! I'll throw new enemies at them
退屈な殻から殻に
From a boring shell to another shell
All right! Lose control! 美しく散りそう
All right! Lose control! About to scatter beautifully
Heads will roll! 逃げ出してやるよ
Heads will roll! I'm going to run away
誰だいったい？ 誰だってどうしたって この理想は無理だろって
Who on earth is it? No matter who, no matter what, they say this ideal is impossible
叶えてこうぜ
Let's make it come true
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
Woo!
しゅどうさんありがとうございました！
Syudou-san, thank you so much!
Thank you Calliope!
叶えてこうぜ
Let's make it come true
でも、まだまだ終わってないすね、みなさん！
But it's not over yet, everyone!
Let's just crash!
ありがとうございます！バイバイしゅどうさん！
Thank you so much! Bye-bye, Syudou-san!
Bye bye, thank you Dead Beats and Calliope!
Bye-bye, thank you Dead Beats and Calliope!
Peace!
Ah, everyone, that was so fun. I really respect Shido-san as an artist. He does a lot of his work himself for his songs. You know, writes and composes and sings and everything. That's really cool. So, big ups to Shido-san.
But, I think it is about time that maybe we get back to the future, the present where I'm performing with all my friends right now.
Yes, but that was a lot of fun. And, as I thought, right on time. It looks like it's time for me to get back to the future, and, go sing with all my friends again back in the present... future? I don't know, if that makes any sense. Let's go! See you there!
Walking an empty road
Nowhere for me to go
lost and lonely
yeah, it's only me
burnt out like candlelight
left blazing through the night
melting slowly
until nothing else is left of me
colored in shades of grey
watching the days pass in front of me
longing to find a way
I can fly away
I'm drifting through this blue, blue world
it's always been clear to me
how cruel the world can be
my shadow's the only one beside me
no love to call my own
no notifs on my phone
sunken silence has engulfed the very life I lead
colored in shades of grey
watching the years pass in front of me
memories I wish would stay
always fade away, I'm lonely in this blue, blue world
though my heart is torn
and my weary wings are worn
just tonight
can't I dream of a better life
with happiness inside?
colored in shades of grey
watching my life pass in front of me
maybe it's not too late
if I can't escape, I'll have to make my own way
colored in shades of grey
palette in hand, I can make a change
I'll try to find the strength
take a breath and paint, bring color to this blue, blue world
Well, beautiful Nerissa, you're so great!
Ah, thank you for coming! Thank you for having me!
After that emotional song, now we're all energetic.
We've got to hype everybody!
Hey, introduce yourself! Happy birthday!
Thank you, thank you, it is my birthday.
But who is this lovely lady I'm singing with right now?
Who could I be?
Hi darlings! This is Hololive English -Advent-'s devilish diva, the one, the only, Nerissa Ravencroft...
...here with you today at your birthday party!
Wow! かっこいい! So cool!
Wow! So cool! So cool!
ありがとうございます!
Thank you very much!
Wow, you're so awesome, Nerissa. Thank you!
Thank you so much for letting me sing your Shoji Meguro song together with you!
We both love Shoji Meguro!
We both have a Shoji Meguro original song!
Yes, we both do!
I was like, my first time performing it got to be with you!
Yeah, no, seriously, it was so fun. It's always fun singing with a friend, so thank you for letting me be a part of it.
We got to harmonize, too!
I did my best to learn the harmonies and, you know, try and remember and stay consistent.
You did amazing! You impressed me!
Thank you so much. Well, I guess we gotta talk about your birthstone, because now we're gonna talk about your birthday, even though it's my birthday.
Do you know your birthstone's a topaz?
Yes! It's so pretty. My birthday is November 21st. I'm a Scorpio and...
...it's so pretty! It matches my...
...my hair, my hair...
...your little hair clip? So true.
My gosh, it just positively lights you up. You're glowing.
How about we take some pictures in front of the stone?
Yeah, let's do it.
Let's do it! Alright, here we go.
Peace? These?
These?
どっちでも! Either one's good.
Either way! Either one's good.
Oh, facing each other?
Feel a little sexy.
Oh, boy.
いい感じ, いい感じ! Very nice. / いい感じ! Use the hashtag!
Great, great! Very nice. / Great! Use the hashtag!
Yes, please. Oh my gosh, please use the hashtag lots and post lots of pictures, okay?
Actually, just so you know, Nerissa, Genta on the drums is the one who played for our original song, Overwrite!
Oh my gosh!
Thank you! ありがとう! Genta, thank you!
Thank you! Thank you! Genta, thank you!
So awesome, really appreciate you, thank you. So many wonderful band members and guests. I feel very lucky and privileged.
And lucky to have you here. / Thank you, Nerissa.
Do you want to drink a water before we start? / That's a great idea, let's do that.
Yeah. / Immediately.
Yes. お水 and...
Yes. Water and...
Okay, yeah, I think we're ready for another song then, how about that?
I am, too, let's do it.
Okay! Together, we can do anything.
Next up is Calliope original song, please enjoy...
...Orpheus!
Alright! Thank you so much, Nerissa, for coming to hang out!
Let's finish this off with a bang! Here we go!
I ain't trying to stress you, I must confess though / My heart's beating to your song
Oh yeah, thinking hurry up Orpheus, time's a wasting
Show me what you really wanna do!
Another late night, aimless dreaming / The day to day starts to call
Still got like a million deadlines, still bleeding red wine / My back up against the wall
I got my headphones on, walk home is long / Dragging feet like I'm born to lose
'Til somehow they're tapping along to you-know-who's song / A melody I can't refuse
I'm outta line, but it's fine, you don't know my name / Safe inside my own mind, I don't feel the shame, okay?
I know I get a little carried away / But we got music when there aren't any words to say!
Cuz in my heart, feel a spark when you look this way / Gimme a sign from the stage when you feel the same
Now I'm in distress, you got me possessed, I might be obsessed / So let me get a little something off my chest
Look, I ain't trying to stress you, I must confess though / My heart's beating to your song
Oh yeah, thinking hurry up Orpheus, time's a wasting
Show me what you really wanna do!
Tonight, it's my turn to show you how obvious I can be
Sometimes it feels like you're playing that guitar for me and only me
Critics so loud, so predictable, they can't see what I can see
You're gonna wind up a star
You got me dancing so bizarre
This distance got me feeling fonder, I wonder if it's enough
Cuz I'm not lying when I'm implying you're all that I've been thinking of
Maybe they'll call me delusional
Baby, this could be real love?
Give me one chance and I'll take
You make me dance the night away
Now it's a game that I've played before / But with the way the scene changed, there is nothing you can blame me for
I'm talking TV screens, magazines, seen you in a couple dreams / Pictures up on every padded wall and floor
Always talking 'bout "no time to desire a lover" / So, why'd you paint your nails up in my favorite color?
I got an attitude, just when it comes to you / So yeah, reality is kinda slipping out of tune
I'm never lost in the groove of somebody new / If it's devotion you're after, I'm staying true
So are you noticing me noticing you noticing me? / No disillusion, but there's not a lot of guarantee
Cuz in my heart, feel a spark when you look this way / Gimme a sign from the stage when you feel the same
You're strumming next to me, now I'm in ecstasy / And for the rest of the week I'm depression-free, alright!
I ain't trying to stress you, I must confess though / My heart's beating to your song
Oh yeah, thinking hurry up Orpheus, time's a wasting
Show me what you really wanna do!
Tonight, it's my turn to show you how obvious I can be
So just as long as you keep playing that guitar...
Yeah!
Critics so loud, so predictable, they can't see what I can see / You're gonna wind up a star!
You got me dancing so bizarre / This distance got me feeling fonder, I wonder if it's enough
Cuz I'm not lying when I'm implying you're all that I've been thinking of
Maybe they'll call me delusional
Baby, this could be real love?
Give me one chance and I'll take
You make me dance the night away
Alright everybody! Today we have a very special band that's gathered today!
They're so cool!
Right? We got to give them a proper introduction, Nerissa.
Yes, we do!
So let's do it! Are you guys ready to meet the band?
Here we go! First up, on the drums, we got...
ジェンタ！
Gento!
そしてベースは、Yu Park！
And then on the bass, it's Yu Park!
そしてギターは、ヨシ！
And on the guitar, it's Yoshi!
そして最後は、今夜のマニピュレーター、hana！
And last but not least, tonight's manipulator is hana!
よし、ネリッサ、やっちゃおう！ / いいね、いこう！
Alright Nerissa, let's take them out! / Sounds good, here we go!
Orpheus、さあ始めよう 最高のステージで
Orpheus, get me going. Taking space with the bass domain.
だからこの場所を盛り上げよう！ 感情がぶつかり合えば、自分たちだけの音楽が作れるはず！
So let's blow this joint! And if the feelings fight, then we can make a little music of our own now!
Orpheus、さあ始めよう 最高のステージで
Orpheus, get me going. Taking space with the bass domain.
なぜ逃げていくの？ 言いたいことは山ほどある！ 次はもっと素晴らしい世界へ！
Why you walking away? I got a lot to say! This is next stop, on the next world!
困らせるつもりはないけれど、認めなきゃ、私たちの心は惹かれ合っている
Ooh! I ain't trying to stress you, I must confess though, my heart's beating to us...
そうなの？
Oh yeah?
だから聞いてよ、Orpheus 今度は私が本当にしたいことを見せてあげる！
So hear me out, Orpheus, I'm thinking next time I'll show you what I really want to do!
バイバイ、ネリッサ！ / 一緒に歌ってくれてありがとう！ / 誕生日おめでとう！ / またね、大好きだよ！
Bye, Nerissa! / Thanks for singing with me! / Happy Birthday! / Yes, see you later, love you too, bye bye!
ねえ あたし いつも 勇気 が 足り ない から 自分 を 大切 に できない んだ
I never seem to have the courage to put myself first...
痛い 目 を みな いと 気 付け や しない んだ あーあ 今日 も キャラメル ペイン です保存
I won't realize unless I've been hurt first. Ah, so I'm in Caramel Pain again.
良い 子 で なんかい られ ないよ だって 世界 は こんなにも 極彩色 で
Don't expect me to be a goody-two-shoes, when the world comes in all shapes, sizes, and colors.
甘ったる くて 苦い し あ 、 待 って 頭痛 いし ヘトヘト で 漂う だけ の 24/7
Too sweet, too bitter, wait, my head hurts, all I do is wade through it in a daze 24/7.
ギリギリ 感情 おさえる なんて もう 無理
I've had it, can't hold my emotions down,
この まま では いら れな いの 日々
Can't live my life like this every day.
ちょっと こわい けど
Scary as it is...
置いて く よ 置いて く よ 置いて く よ 今 まで 手 にした イデオロギー も スタイル も
I'll leave it behind, I'll leave it all behind, my ideologies and style too.
壊れ ちゃっても 今 が いい よ だって あたし は あたし の まま で ずっと いたい んだもん
Even if they break, now is better, 'cause I wanna be who I am forever.
ルート ？ ムード ？ どう でも いーよ トゥーザ ネクスト もっと 危ない こと したら 勝 ちなん でしょ
The route? The mood? Who cares? To the next, who dares wins, right?
何 を 犠牲 に し たって しょうが ない んだ よ フロム マイ ベッド この 胸の痛み だけ 抱いて
If sacrifices must be made, they will be. From my bed, holding on to my hurt alone.
あーあ 今日 も キャラメル ペイン です
Ah, so I'm in Caramel Pain again.
ミルフィーユ みたい に はぐらかし たって いつか バレ ちゃう よ 腐っ ちゃう よ保存
Layer it and hide it like a mille-feuille, but it'll fall away, it'll all rot.
痛い とか 素直 に 君 に 言え て れ ば 今頃 何 か 変わっ て た の かも ね
If I'd told you about all my hurt honestly, would things have been different by now?
好き な アニメ も なくなっ ちゃう し
The anime I love go away,
好きな人 だって い なくなっ ちゃうん だ
Even the people I love go away.
寂しく なっちゃうな
It's all so sad.
大切なこと は ただ 一つ だけ さ
But there's only one thing that matters:
もう 後悔 しない ように 前 を 向い て 生きるということ ！
Leave no stone unturned, live life with my head held high!
置いて く よ 置いて く よ 置いて く よ 今 まで 手 にした イデオロギー も スタイル も
I'll leave it behind, I'll leave it all behind, my ideologies and style too.
汚れ ちゃっても 気 にしないよ だって あたし は あたし に 恋し て たい んだもん
They may get stained, but I'll take it, 'cause I wanna be in love with myself forever.
愛してるよ 愛してるよ 愛してるよ さよなら なんて 涙 が 出 ちゃう けど
I love you, I love you all the way, saying goodbye brings out the tears, but...
何 を 犠牲 に し たって しょうが ない んだ よ フロム マイ ベッド この 胸の痛み だけ 抱いて
If sacrifices must be made, they will be. From my bed, holding on to my hurt alone.
あーあ 今日 も キャラメル ペイン です
Ah, so I'm in Caramel Pain again.
ねえ あたし いつも 勇気 が 足り ない から 自分 を 大切 に できない んだ
I never seem to have the courage to put myself first...
痛い くらい なら 少し 我慢 する んだ あーあ 今日 も キャラメル ペイン です
If it's going to hurt, I'll just bear it. Ah, so I'm in Caramel Pain again.
イェーイ！ 最高！
Yay! Awesome!
やったー！やったー！保存
Hooray! Hooray!
久しぶりだけど、ウェルカム！ / ありがとう！ / おめでとう！
It's been a while, but welcome! / Thank you! / Congratulations!
自己紹介お願いします！
Please introduce yourself!
彗星の如く現れたスターの原石！アイドルVTuberの星街すいせいです！カリオペ、誕生日おめでとう！
It's the diamond in the rough who appeared like a comet! Idol VTuber Hoshimachi Suisei! Calli, happy birthday!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
そしてね、メジャーデビューも4周年？
And also, your major debut's 4th anniversary, right?
そうだよね！すごい、おめでとう！_
That's right! Wow, congratulations to both of us!
そう、一緒に歌いましたよね！
Yes, we sang together last time!
そう、4年前の、メジャーデビューした時のライブで。
Yeah, four years ago, at the live concert for your major debut.
一緒に歌わせてもらいましたね。
We got to sing together, didn't we?
懐かしい。
So nostalgic.
ねえ、懐かしい。これ、なんかこんなんもやってなくない？
Right, so nostalgic. Didn't we also do something like this?
やりました。たくさんやりました。
We did. We did it a lot.
やったよね。
We did, didn't we?
やばいよね、めっちゃいい思い出ですよね。
That's crazy, it's such a great memory.
覚えてくれたね、それ。
You remembered that.
ね、久しぶりに歌えて嬉しいね。
Right, I'm glad we could sing it again after a long time.
懐かしいポイント。
A nostalgic point.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
そうですね、今回「Caramel Pain」一緒に歌いました。一番好きな星街すいせい曲です！
Yes, we sang "Caramel Pain" together this time. It's my favorite Hoshimachi Suisei song!
わあ！嬉しい！
Wow! I'm so happy!
イェーイ、やった。
Yay, we did it.
めっちゃいい感じだったね、ハモリとかもね。
It felt really good, the harmonies and everything too.
たくさん練習しました。
We practiced a lot.
ねえ、本当に綺麗だったぜ。
Right, it was really beautiful.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
ちなみに、ほら、ピカピカストーン。
By the way, look, the sparkling stones.
おお、わお、ビューティフル！
Oh, wow, beautiful!
うん、素敵ですよね。
Yeah, they're lovely, aren't they?
素敵。
Lovely.
え、すいせい先輩、あの私知ってるけど、誕生日はいつですか？
Um, Suisei-senpai, I already know, but when is your birthday?
私は3月の22。
Mine is March 22nd.
March.
22.
22nd.
そうですね。
That's right.
先月、先月...
Last month, last month...
そう、先月。
Yes, last month.
です。
Yes.
ですので、ほら、アクアマリンが誕生石...
So, you see, aquamarine is the birthstone...
アクアマリンだ！
It's aquamarine!
もうぴったりよね。私知らなかったよ、自分の誕生石アクアマリンって。
It's a perfect match. I didn't know my birthstone was aquamarine.
そう、ぴったりですよ。マジで最高。
Yes, it's perfect. Seriously the best.
ねえ、同じ色だよ。もう。
Right, it's the same color. Really.
同じ色。最高だぜ。
Same color. It's the best.
めっちゃ素敵ですよ。
It's so lovely.
めっちゃ綺麗だから、一緒に写真撮りましょう！
It's so beautiful, let's take a picture together!
あ、撮ろう。
Ah, let's take one.
いいですか？レッツゴー。
Is it okay? Let's go.
イェーイ。
Yay.
私ね、やりたいものある。
I have something I want to do.
オッケー。
Okay.
これ、分かる？何のポーズか。
Do you know what pose this is?
No. ジョジョじゃない？
No. Is it Jojo?
違うよ。
No, it's not.
What is this?
Gold on Belt!
そう！
Exactly!
これめちゃめちゃいいよね。
This is really cool.
ありがとう。Thank you so much. え、ちゃんと見てくれた、ありがとう。
Thank you. Thank you so much. Oh, you watched it properly, thank you.
もちろん！大好きな曲ですよ。
Of course! It's a song I love.
Thank you so much, senpai.
え、ちなみに、Everybody really quick, before we keep going, おしらせあります！
Oh, by the way, everybody really quick, before we keep going, we have an announcement!
Yes, quick announcement about members only.
メンバー限定アンコールがありますよ。
There will be a members-only encore!
やったー！
Yay!
A solo session, and we need to pick one song that I just performed with the amazing guests, and, uh, I'm gonna do a solo version of it.
Yes, so you have one minute starting now. 1分ありますよ、vote. あの、カリオペはソロで歌いますよ。さっきゲストと一緒に歌った曲。
Yes, so you have one minute starting now. You have 1 minute, vote. Um, Calliope will sing it solo. The song I just sang with the guest.
Please vote, everybody, you have one minute, go!
1分ね。この後のメン限でソロで歌ってくれるらしいですよ。
1 minute. Apparently she'll sing it solo in the members-only stream after this.
えー、全部聴きたいよー！
Eh, I want to hear them all!
そうだね、全部めちゃめちゃいい曲、すべての曲。
Right, they are all very, very good songs, all of them.
ねえ、やばいよ。
Right, it's crazy.
But only one.
ねえ、1曲だけですよ。選んでくださいね。
Right, only one song. Please choose, okay?
選んでね。Please, お願いします。
Please choose. Please, I beg you.
どれがいいかな、どれがいいかな。
Which one is good, which one is good?
Okay, お願いします。あ、楽しみ。頑張ります。
Okay, please. Oh, I'm looking forward to it. I'll do my best.
ねえ。
Right.
いや、カリオペ本当にね、4...4年。メジャーデビューして4年。
Well, Calliope really, 4... 4 years. 4 years since major debut.
本当に駆け抜けてきたよね。
You've really run through it all, haven't you?
そう、いろいろやってますよ。
Yes, I'm doing all kinds of things.
ねえ。なんかアニメのタイアップとかもね、たくさん決まって。
Right. And you've gotten a lot of anime tie-ins and things too.
来ました、来ました。
They've come, they've come.
ねえ、嬉しい。
Right, I'm glad.
So, my dream...
そうですね、夢が叶った。
That's right, my dream came true.
ねえ、すごい。めっちゃ嬉しい。
Right, amazing. I'm so happy.
ありがとう、皆さんのおかげで。
Thank you, thanks to everyone.
素敵な先輩のおかげでも。My inspiration. Thank you so much, everybody!
And also thanks to my wonderful senpai. My inspiration. Thank you so much, everybody!
イェーイ、最高。
Yay, the best.
So, let's keep shooting for the moon.
そうだよ。
That's right.
Let's see. Okay, well, everybody is writing what they want...
おお、すごいすごい。今好きな曲...
Oh, amazing, amazing. Currently, your favorite song...
おお、すごいすごい。
Oh, amazing, amazing.
そうだよね、すごい。Many, many, many...
Right, amazing. Many, many, many...
お、投票が？
Oh, the voting?
Go, go, go! Choose, choose, choose! 選んで、選んで。
Go, go, go! Choose, choose, choose! Choose, choose.
選んだ？始まってる？
Did you choose? Has it started?
投票難しくない？長めにやりますってよ。
Isn't voting hard? They say they'll keep it open a bit longer.
うん、オッケー。A little bit longer.
Yeah, okay. A little bit longer.
I love... Yeah! Thank you, thank you.
あ、今からスタート？今からスタート。オッケー。
Oh, is it starting from now? Starting from now! Ok.
今からスタート！Yeah, okay, no problem.
Starting from now! Yeah, okay, no problem.
Push, push! Go, go, go! Push, please!
ちなみに、カリオペの他のお知らせがあるんだけど。
By the way, Calliope has another announcement...
おっ！あの、カバー曲もリリースします！
Oh! Um, I will also be releasing a cover song!
Yes, check it out. The cover song is 'In My Head' by Natori. Okay?
Check it out! In my head!
I like song!
You like it? Yeah, me too.
In my head! In my head! Yeah!
Yes, please listen to it. 聞いてくださいね。
Yes, please listen to it. Please listen to it.
そう、あの、このライブのあと。そして、そのあとはメンバー限定！はい。
Yeah, um, after this live. And after that, members-only! Yes.
はい、そして、We have goods! Goods are going to be released very soon, so I wanted to tell you guys about the goods.
Yes, and we have goods! Goods are going to be released very soon, so I wanted to tell you guys about the goods.
グッズもありますので、limited、limitedもありますので、ちゃんとお伝えしたかったけど。
We have goods as well, limited ones too, so I really wanted to let you know.
最後のほう、配信の最後のほうは詳細を流します。おー！
Towards the end, at the end of the stream, we will show the details. Oh!
But in about 2 minutes, 本当にもうすぐ、出るから。あのそのURL。
But in about two minutes, really soon, it will be out. That URL.
準備しといて。そうですね、準備して。
Get ready for it. Yes, get ready.
心の準備もして。Yes, okay.
Get your mind ready too. Yes, okay.
Oh, check it out! Here it is! Yes!
えっ、かっこいい！Yeah, yes!
Whoa, cool! Yeah, yes!
Dark fantasy, Calliope! Cool! Calliope!
Dark fantasy. Thank you, I'm so cool! すごい。
Dark fantasy. Thank you, I'm so cool! Amazing.
I'm like, super dark fantasy game boss.
I'm like, a super dark fantasy game boss.
あの、魔王みたい。魔王。Yes.
Um, like a Demon King. Demon King. Yes.
魔王 is English nani?
What is 'Maou' in English?
魔王、like, uh... なんて言えばいいかな。
Maou... like, uh... how should I say...
Dark... Dark... Dark King? Dark King.
Dark King! Yes!
英語うまいよ、すいちゃん。Nice.
Your English is so good, Suichan. Nice.
あ、投票終了。Ah, voting's over by the way.
Ah, voting is over by the way. Voting's over!
Voting is over! It's done, yay! Thank you so much.
Oh my god, I'm excited to see what you guys chose.
Now then, we should sing one more song then, shouldn't we? Because...
Oh, but look out for the goods! Goods URL is dropping soon, there's limited merch.
チェックしてね、グッズ買ってね。よろしくね。
Check it out, buy the goods. Please do.
Okay, so... たくさん休みましたね。だから。うん。
Okay, so... we took a lot of rest, so... yeah.
Let's sing one more song! Yeah! もう一曲、一緒に歌いたいと思います。
Let's sing one more song! Yeah! I'd like to sing one more song together.
いいですか？皆さん。いいですか？
Is that okay, everyone? Is that okay?
Okay.
ふん、じゃあ、二人ならやれるさ。やれるさ。
Hmm, then, if it's the two of us, we can do it! We can do it!
Next song is... Gold Unbalance!
不確かな物語に
In a story filled with uncertainties,
勝ち取るはアイデンティティー
we struggle to win our identity.
あれやこれと
Trying this and that,
手を替え品を替え
changing our tactics and methods.
ドキりと胸を刺す激情
Passion stabs the chest, making it skip a beat.
感情はノンフィクションで喜怒哀楽
The emotions are non-fiction, joy, anger, sorrow, pleasure,
一心同体 一切合切の衝動
two bodies, one soul, all of our impulses.
失敗も成功も味わえ
Taste both failure and success,
我らゴールデンバディ
we are the golden buddy.
意味なんてないような世界で
In this world that seems meaningless,
偶然を重ねた光
light formed by layers of coincidence.
脈打つ鼓動 誰にもなれない
Pulse-pounding heartbeat, we cannot become anyone else,
言葉を紡いでいこう
so weave your own words.
舐めんなよ
Don't look down on us!
小さな勇気ひとつありゃ十分
A little bit of courage is enough.
強気に高みへと
With confidence, climb to the heights,
圧倒絶頂 二人ならやれるさ
overwhelming, climax, if it's the two of us, we can do it!
Yeah!
Back-to-back, no matter what, 背負ったもん武器に変わる spot
Back-to-back, no matter what, what we carry turns into weapons, spot.
段違い遠くまで飛ばす shout, 誰も邪魔できねぇこの route
A shout that flies far, different in level, nobody can block this route.
1等2等3通りってはなから loser, うざいくらい貪欲に
1st, 2nd, 3rd, that kind of ranking, a loser from the start, greedy to the point of being annoying,
ハート地獄からかっぱらっちまえ
steal the heart right out of hell.
Loop 輪廻じゃない Route は無限に
It's not a loop of reincarnation, the route is infinite,
ありふれた道じゃない 荊の道を好む玄人
it's not a common path, an expert who loves the thorny path.
Hahaha...
盛大にもう笑えばいいさ
Let's laugh grandly now!
才能煩悩のグラデーション
The gradation of talent and worldly desires,
どうせならぐちゃぐちゃにしてよ
if we're going to do it, let's make a mess of it.
始めたのならやり切る覚悟を
If you've started, have the determination to see it through,
敗者と勝者の duet
a duet of the loser and the winner.
劣等感 弾き出された不条理の屑
Inferiority complex, scraps of absurdity that were expelled,
振り払え貪欲に
shake it off, greedily,
志は消えない
the ambition will not disappear,
2人ならやれるさ
if it's the two of us, we can do it!
生きるってなんだ サボった者勝ちか
What does it mean to live? Does the slacker win?
そんなもの握りつぶせ
Crush such things!
上辺じゃいられない
We can't just be on the surface,
エンタメライダ
entertain-rider,
人生賭け駆け抜け
betting your life and running through,
絶望も栄光も
both despair and glory,
Lemme see you fight back
どうなったって何も変わらないんだって
No matter what happens, nothing will change,
ミームされた現実に囚われて
trapped in a memed reality,
This life where we're stuck taking chances
飽き飽きしてんでしょ？？
you're tired of it, aren't you??
We're living in a world with no direction
Reach out with our light 'till we make a connection
Tearing the walls apart
Facing it all, side by side
Once again, it's us against the world
舐めんじゃねーよ
Don't underestimate us!
本能をヒリつかせて
Let your instincts burn,
本物見せつけろ
Show them the real thing!
圧倒絶頂
Overwhelming climax!
アンバランスを
Dance in the unbalance...
踊れ
Dance!
Thanks for watching, everybody!
Thank you to my guest! Thank you to the band!
Thank you to everyone who came to hang out at Members'...
この後もよろしく！
Enjoy the rest too!
Yeah, and point is good.
That's about all, you guys. I'm Mori Calliope.
Peace out, see ya!
Woo! Let's go! Yeah!
Bye!
Hey, what's up, you crazy skeleton...
I mean...
Dearest Dead Beats, the hour is finally upon us.
The sale of Mori Calliope's birthday celebration goods is about to begin.
On this most auspicious day, you've been granted a great blessing by Death herself.
A most fortunate occurrence for thee that such a glorious chest should appear before thine eyes.
Let's take a peek at what the Goddess of Death herself has to offer, shall we?
The journey ahead is long and arduous. It would do thee good to prepare for it with such luxurious treasures.
Firstly, wouldst thou find comfort in dear Death's embrace?
If it be so, take some warmth along thy journey
with this very large, rollable blanket featuring a most intimidating and battle-ready maiden—
yours truly, designed by my favorite dark fantasy artist, Shimhaq!
The maiden in question possesses artworks and masks from this particular individual, so
I'd be most elated if you bought it for yourself.
Lay it across your bed, hang it on your wall, take it with you on an outing—think of the possibilities!
Secondly, whilst on thy noble journey, thou mayst come to need a spark of aid.
If it be so, take one of these amulets: the emblem of a knight to boost your strength,
the emblem of a samurai to grant you additional dexterity,
the emblem of a priestess to bestow additional health to thy weary body,
and lastly, the emblem of a necromancer to grant thee additional intelligence.
Alas, as fortune be a fickle mistress, thou mayst only receive one in a set.
I pray thee be granted the boon most favorable to thy quest.
Or... or you could just purchase them all separately if you're looking to speedrun the experience, I suppose.
Thirdly, I present to thee the shining centerpiece of this valuable collection.
Take a moment of repose and sit beside this warm and healing light, granted unto thee by Death herself.
A lantern to revive thee as many times as needed throughout even the most daunting of journeys.
May it light thy way to victory... or to sweet dreams, whichever is preferred.
Enjoy an elegant design chosen specifically by myself.
And of course, how could one continue a journey into vast and unforgiving lands without a source of healing?
Rejuvenate thyself with this generous flask, or rather, glass, that seems to refill endlessly upon rest at your lantern.
At least, I think it will. There really are no guarantees in this life, but give it a try yourself, see if the myths are true.
Enjoy your favorite beverage during a night of exploring your favorite fantasy scenarios.
But naturally, it would do me no good to leave thee without a... I don't know, bedtime story? To put this enchanting collection into context.
So, please enjoy a short, audiobook-style recording of a fantastical story written by yours truly.
Believe it or not, we are the stars of this tale, so enjoy it on a rainy evening wrapped warmly in Death's embrace.
The... the blanket, I mean. You can use the flask also for like, drinking at the same time, I don't know, just, you should really buy the full set!
And definitely do, because lucky skeletons who act fast and purchase the entire set will be granted a hand-signed postcard
with a special color variant of Shimhaq's masterpiece rendition of Death herself.
The hand-signed option is in limited supply, so you must be swift.
For those that are unable to secure this extremely rare offering in time, do not fret.
By purchasing the entire set, a duplicated foil-stamped signature postcard will be sent as a bonus for your purchase.
That is all from me, Death's Maiden and dark fantasy enjoyer, Mori Calliope.
This year's goods are very different from my usual, but I wanted to pay tribute to a genre that I love so dearly and has really made every day of my job so wonderful and happy.
I am so grateful to you guys for coming to enjoy my show as well.
Comment and let me know what your favorite part was, be sure to like the concert so others may be recommended it, and subscribe if you enjoy Mori Calliope!
With that, I bid thee farewell. And happy birthday to me!
Happy Birthday to me!!
6 birthdays, huh?! This time was even more special than usual.
Much love to my guests, my Dead Beats, my band,
and everyone who wants to see me fly!
Let's have an even happier year, together!!
- Calliope Mori